# Michael Gebhart

## **Gameplay Programmer**

Team player with a focus on C++ and Unreal Engine. Professional game development experience with UE 3, 4 and 5.

Motivated to learn new skills and build on my C++ skills with the goal of leading technical teams myself one day.

Inspired to make games reaching players worldwide!

**Portfolio**: www.michael-gebhart.com • **GitHub**: www.github.com/m-gebhart **Mail**: mail@michael-gebhart.com • **LinkedIn**: www.linkedin.com/in/m-gebhart

WORK EXPERIENCE		
09/2024 - present	Abstraction Games B.V Valkenswaard, NL (Remote)  Programmer (regular) working on unannounced incubation project.	
09/2023 - 08/2024	<ul> <li>Abstraction Games B.V Valkenswaard, NL (Remote)</li> <li>Jr. Programmer resuming work on Gigantic: Rampage Edition (Gearbox Publishing, 2024)</li> <li>Post-Launch Support by using C++ and C# to write UE3 features and tasks:         <ul> <li>Applied new metric system for better match performance rating behaviour.</li> <li>Multiple new upgrade abilities for heroes from initial roster.</li> <li>Extended clone AI behaviour (Kajir's specialty, most recently introduced hero).</li> </ul> </li> <li>Utilized JSON to remove hero bugs and exploits based on player feedback.</li> <li>Further UI programming with C++, UC, Kismet and Flash, AS, Scaleform, e.g.:         <ul> <li>Redesign of UI screens (e.g., character selection, loadouts) in collaboration with design team.</li> <li>Finalized voice UI system in collaboration with engine team.</li> </ul> </li> </ul>	
03/ - 07/2023	<ul> <li>Localization, tutorial UI displays and gamepad navigation fixes (certification).</li> <li>Abstraction Games B.V Valkenswaard, NL (Remote)</li> <li>C++ Programming Intern for Gigantic: Rampage Edition (Gearbox Publishing, 2024)</li> <li>UI programming for UE3 project with C++, UC and Flash, AS, Scaleform:</li> </ul>	
	<ul> <li>Redesign of menu and HUD elements (e.g., voice, in-game and shield system, new HUD indications for skill status timers).</li> <li>Better console UI navigation by creating new functionalities for footer action bar (e.g., custom controls, animation options for button prompts).</li> </ul>	
11/2020 – 12/2022	Macromedia University of Applied Sciences - Cologne, GER Student Assistant for Game Design & Development programme management	
11/2020 - 03/2021	<ul> <li>Adventure Works LLC - Miami, US (Remote)</li> <li>Game Programming Intern for Far Away (later revealed as Ari Baktu and the Anytime Elevator)</li> <li>Used C++ and UE4 / 5 to assist development of a side-scrolling narrative action game.</li> <li>Supported the core gameplay team with rapid prototyping, bugfixing, gameplay features and in-engine level design tools.</li> </ul>	
EDUCATION		

**Cologne Game Lab**, institute of Cologne University of Applied Sciences (TH Köln)

BA Digital Games - Game Programming

09/2018 - 08/2023

### **SHIPPED COMMERCIAL TITLES**

• Gigantic: Rampage Edition

Release: April 9<sup>th</sup>, 2024

Genre: MOBA / 3<sup>rd</sup> Person

Action Online Game

O Developer: Abstraction Games B.V. (Original release by Motiga)

 I joined the project in March 2023 to support its latter phase of development. Following its release in April 2024, I stayed on the project until July 2024 to incorporate as much player feedback as possible (before then being allocated to another internal incubation project (tba)).

### **ACADEMIC TEAM PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

The Big Banger (2021)	Gameplay Programmer • Team of Six • Unity, C#, AR Foundation
Mobile AR Educational Game	<ul> <li>Player feedback systems (e.g., movement, audio, UI).</li> </ul>
	• Control and input systems (i.e., translating 2D touch input to a 3D space).
Mayhaemsters (2020)	Project Lead, Gameplay Programmer • Team of Five • Unreal Engine 4, C++
Local Multiplayer Action Game	Pitched initial concept.
	<ul> <li>Team management by overseeing tasks and deadlines.</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Co-Implemented game systems (e.g., input, vehicle movement,</li> </ul>
	animation, audio, UI).
Underground Berlin (2020)	JavaScript Programmer, Web Designer • Team of Four • HTML / CSS, JavaScript
Alternate Reality Game	Scripted static and dynamic websites as part of connected puzzle games.
A Dystopian Murder Show (2019)	Gameplay Programmer • Team of Five • Unity, C#
Action Platformer	<ul> <li>Created majority of game systems (e.g., controls, combat, UI,</li> </ul>
	animations).
	Polished game for release on itch.io.

### **SKILLS**

Technical Experiences:	• C++, C#
	<ul> <li>JavaScript, HTML / CSS, ActionScript, Scaleform, UnrealScript</li> </ul>
	• Unreal Engine 3 - 5, OpenGL, Godot, Unity, FMOD, Rider, Adobe Animate
	Git, Perforce
	Vegas Movie Studio, MS Office Suit, Jira
Languages:	German (native), English